A Guide to the Pittsylvania County (Va.) Records, 1788-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Pittsylvania County (Va.) Records, 1788-1864
The Library of Virginia
0007697108
.35 cu.ft (1 box)
Pittsylvania County (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Pittsylvania County.
Biographical Information
Pittsylvania County was named in honor of William Pitt, first earl of Chatham, the English statesman. It was formed from Halifax County in 1766. The county court first met on 26 June 1767. The county seat is Chatham.
Scope and Content
Pittsylvania County (Va.) Records, 1788-1864, includes miscellaneous records from the following series: Judgments, Writs of Habeas Corpus, Naturalization Records, Letters to the County Court and Resolutions, Mutual Assurance Company Declarations, Petitions, Soldiers' Aid Society Records, and Soldiers' Fund Report.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Pittsylvania County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Pittsylvania County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Pittsylvania County.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Pittsylvania County.
Contents List
- Indian Nan versus John Worsham, 1788 August
  Plaintiff was a Native American suing for her freedom.
- Joseph Hubbard versus Richard Gross, Sr., 1807 March
  Lock of human hair included in suit as exhibit.
- Archibald Snead versus Matilda Snead, 1833 May
  Petition for divorce.
- Bank of Virginia versus William M. Williams, Jr., etc., 1724-1731
  Includes issue of Danville (Va.) Reporter, 8 March 1834
- Writs of Habeas Corpus, 1861-1864
  Involves individuals falsely imprisoned or were impressed into military service during the Civil War.
- Alexander Brown, 1811
  Native of Scotland.
- Letters to County Court, Orders, and Resolutions, 1799-1864
- Mutual Assurance Declarations of Permenas Williams, 1805
- Special Police Force, 1865
  List of members.
- Petitons and correspondence of Captain William H. Werth, 1861
- Soldiers' Aid Society, 1861-1862
- Soldiers' Fund Report, 1864